Guide to the M. L. Rosenthal Papers ca. 1930-1996 MSS 45
New York University Libraries, Publisher
- Series VI: Biographical material
  - Notes on criticism, undated (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - NYU-related, undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Orals, undated (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Playbills, undated (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Playbills, undated (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Playbills, undated (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Poetics Institute, undated (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Present Tense (including correspondence and mss), undated (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Present Tense (including correspondence and mss), undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Publishers, undated (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - School notebooks, undated (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - Student notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Student notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Student notes (incl. poetry), undated (Box 6, Folder 95)
  - Student papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Student papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Student papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Student papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Syllabi, undated (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Tax and legal papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Tearsheets with MLR poems, undated (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Trips, undated (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Undergrad comps: bibliography, undated (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Undergrad comps: grammar, undated (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Undergrad comps: linguistics, undated (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Undergraduate exams, undated (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - University of Pennsylvania, undated (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Yeats seminar, undated (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Address books and calendars (no folders), undated (Box 7)
  - (Accretions 2000) misc. notes and letters pulled from Rosenthal's books while cataloguing them at Fales, undated (Box 8)
  - (Accretions 2000) materials from Rosenthal's office at the English Department, undated (Box 8)
- Series VII: Production files
  - Blue Boy on Skates, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Genius of Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Genius of Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Genius of Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Genius of Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Genius of Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Genius of Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Genius of Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - New Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - New Modern Poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Pinocchio, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pinocchio, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Pinocchio, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pinocchio, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Pinocchio, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pinocchio, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Poetry and the Common Life, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The Poet's Art (proofs), undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Poet's Art, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Poet's Art, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Poet's Art, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - The Poet's Art, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sailing Into the Unknown, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Sailing Into the Unknown, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Selected Poems... by W. B. Yeats, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Selected Poems... by W. B. Yeats, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - She, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Series VIII: Photographs
  - Photographs of MLR, family, and others (in archivally-sound photograph sleeves), undated (Box Sleeves)
- Series IX: Audiovisual [Research copies may not be available for these materials yet. Check with the Fales archivist.]
  - Cassette tapes, two reel-to-reel tapes, and one microfilm (no folders), undated (Box Tapes)
- Oversize
  - Series 5B, folder 15-misc. printed material, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Series 6, folder 4b-biographical/Juvenilia, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
Separated Material
The M. L. Rosenthal Library, comprising some 5,000 titles, was donated to the NYU libraries along with the papers. The library was sorted, primary texts were catalogued for the Fales Library, secondary texts were sent to the open stacks.